Sanjay Ghurahu Yadav



ysanjay4444@gmail.com



8169236672/9594443688



linkedin.com/in/sanjay-yadav-327a72163

Summary

Worked as a Professional Asp. Net MVC/ SQL Developer at Cognizant solutions for Optum client in Health insurance domain. Also has worked in Indian Insurance Domain for Tata-Aig as a developer of Insurance based products. Experienced and proficient in C#, .Net Framework, SQL. Have worked in team and friendly environment and ready to take up new challenges.

Experience



🌓 Software Engineer

Cognizant

May 2022 - Dec 2022 (8 months)

Worked with Optum Healthcare Service provider in development of new application functionalities related to healthcare domain.

- 1.Developed Market Initiative functionality using which providers belonging to specific state with specific assigned roles only can will have access to all details of insured.
- 2. Worked on development of functionality using which insured can upload details of the dependent.

Senior Software Engineer

CitiusTech

Aug 2021 - Apr 2022 (9 months)

Have worked for Baker Hughes(BH),(Oil and Gas Company) for developing application that interact with different sensor devices for collection, modulation and providing a way to present the same to the user. BH makes use of System 1 which is self developed software and acts like a OPC UA Server . System 1 works on OPC UA Protocol for transmission of data in between client and server.

- Roles & Responsibilities
- 1. Adding new functionalities to System 1 which is OPC UA Server using C#. Net language and Postgres as database.
- 2. Testing our code on different level like Unit Test, SI Testing, LI Testing.
- 3. Deploying our code using Git and Devops.
- 4. Knowledge sharing sessions with client and team related to changes made to the system and working on any concerns if reported.
- Major Achievements from Project
- 1. Have developed the importing of tags functionality for System 1 application.

System Engineer

Tata Consultancy Services Jun 2018 - Aug 2021 (3 years 3 months) Provided service to Tata AIG General Insurance Company Limited, Indian general insurance company and a joint venture between the Tata Group and American International Group. It also offer a wide range of products for businesses and Individual in health Insurance.

- Responsibilities
- 1. Worked as C# .Net Developer for building insurance domain products using Genisys Configurator tool.
- 2.Implementing premium computation logic for products based on the requirement of client using C# and PLSQL.
- 3. Completing Post-Development process (Unit Testing, FI Documentation, Deployment checklist creation, UAT Testing).
- 4.Provding support to production module for critical issues and handling client escalation.
- 5. Completing documentation related to Change Request(CR) for FI process.
- · Major Achievements from Project
- 1.First Product developed which was integrated with Business Rule Engine(BRE), which is external service used for computational logic of products.
- 2.Implemented IRDA Compliance Long Term changes and GST changes within short period of time for which got appreciation from client.

Education

Ramrao Adik Institute of Technology

Bachelor's degree, Electronics Engineering

2014 - 2018

Completed BE in Electronics Engineering from Mumbai University with 7.9 CGPA



2012 - 2014

Completed HSC from Maharashtra Board with 85.38%.

Guru Nanak High School

Secondary School

Completed SSC from Maharashtra Board with 90.55%.

Licenses & Certifications

🕠 Microsoft Azure Fundamental - Udemy

Training in Angular JS/MVC Framework - Tata Consultancy Services

Skills

C# • ASP.NET • ASP.NET MVC • ASP.NET Core • Git • Angular • SQL • ASP.NET Web API

Honors & Awards

Employee of Quarter - Tata Consultancy Services

First Employee of Quarter(Oct 2019-Dec 2019) for Project.



Appreciation for Quality Work - Tata Consultancy Services

Sep 2019

Have got Appreciation and Gems for quality work done from Team Lead.